<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
	  
<GameData>  
	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV_MEC_ANGMAR_DESC">
			<Text>Angmar Kingdom</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV_MEC_ANGMAR_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Angmar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV_MEC_ANGMAR_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Angmar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV5_MEC_ANGMAR_TEXT_1">
			<Text>
				Angmar was the realm founded by the evil Nazgûl leader, who became known as the Witch-king of Angmar in TA 1300.  The kingdom was located in the far north of the Misty Mountains. The land was known in part for its cold weather, mostly snowing. Shortly after the Kingdom of Angmar was founded, it waged a war against the Dúnedain realms of Arthedain, Cardolan and Rhudaur. The weakest of Arnor's sub-kingdoms, Rhudaur, was conquered by the Witch-king, who replaced its Dúnedain leader with one of the native 'Hill-men'. Then in TA 1409, Angmar attacked Cardolan and Rivendell and destroyed all the settlements within except Cardolan's capital, the Barrow-downs. After the Great Plague, the last of Cardolan's people died allowing Angmar to send the Barrow-wights into the downs. During the time of TA 1974, Angmar multiplied its forces and launched a final assault on Arthedain, who no longer had any allies to come to their aid. Subsequently, Angmar took its capital Fornost, thereby destroying the last northern kingdom of the Dúnedain. Sometime later, Prince Eärnur - thirty-third and last King of Gondor - arrived to aid Arthedain, but he was too late. His army defeated the forces of Angmar in the Battle of Fornost, and the Witch-King fled to Mordor leaving Angmar to fall apart in TA 1975. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE] Your Lord Sauron calls upon you again Witch King, King of Angmar and Lord of the Nazgul. Will you sit in victory upon the thrones of your enemies? Or will your armies be crushed as you run away in retreat? Can you build a civilization that will stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV5_MEC_ANGMAR">
			<Text>Angmar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_BORDERLANDS">
			<Text>Borderlands</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_FORODWAITH">
			<Text>Forodwaith</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_ANGMAR">
			<Text>Angmar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_NORTH_DOWNS">
			<Text>North Downs</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_CARN_DUN">
			<Text>Carn Dum</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_GOROTHLAD">
			<Text>Gorothlad</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_EASTERN_ANGMAR">
			<Text>Eastern Angmar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_HIMBAR">
			<Text>Himbar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_NAN_GURTH">
			<Text>Nan Gurth</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_MALENHAD">
			<Text>Malenhad</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_URUGARTH">
			<Text>Urugarth</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_DOR_DAIDELOS">
			<Text>Dor Daidelos</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_AUGHAIRE">
			<Text>Aughaire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_FOROCHEL">
			<Text>Forochel</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_DUVUMEN">
			<Text>Duvumen</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_DONNVAIL">
			<Text>Donnvail</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_FASACH_FALROLD">
			<Text>Fasach Falrold</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_IMLAD_BALCHORTH">
			<Text>Imlad Balchorth</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_GATH_ULOR">
			<Text>Gath Ulor</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_WEATHERTOP">
			<Text>Weathertop</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_DEADMANS_DIKE">
			<Text>Deadman's Dike</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_BARROW_DOWNS">
			<Text>Barrow Downs</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MEC_WITCH_KING">
			<Text>Witch King</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MEC_WITCH_KING_PEDIA">
			<Text>Witch King of Angmar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MEC_WITCH_KING">
			<Text>
				The Witch-king of Angmar was the leader of the Nazgûl or Ringwraiths, and Sauron's second-in-command in the Second and Third Ages. Once a king of men, he was corrupted by one of the nine Rings of Power given to the lords of men and became an undead wraith in the service of Sauron. The Lord of the Nazgûl reappeared in TA 1300 in the north near the lost realm of Arnor. There he founded the kingdom of Angmar. It was after the formation of Angmar and several conflicts with the Dúnedain of the North that the Lord of the Nazgûl received the title of Witch-king, Lord of Angmar. He then began his open war campaign with the three divided kingdoms of Arnor (Arthedain, Rhudaur, and Cardolan). In TA 1356, the Witch-king invaded the kingdom of Rhudaur and replaced the Dúnedain king of the land with a hill chief allied to Angmar. King Argeleb of Arthedain was killed trying to defend Rhudaur against Angmar. In TA 1409 the troops of the Witch-King assaulted the fortress of Amon Sûl and burned the tower, during which conflict king Arveleg of Arthedain was killed. The Witch-King then invaded and destroyed the kingdom of Cardolan. Then the Witch-King invaded Arthedain and came close to destroying it but King Araphor with the help of the elves of Lindon and Rivendell managed to defeat the invading forces. Soon, the only resistance against the Witch-king's forces was the western kingdom of Arthedain. The Witch-king continued his war for hundreds of years. In TA 1636, the Witch-king sent wights to the Barrow-downs in Cardolan in order to prevent the rebirth of the kingdom. The Witch-king claimed ultimate victory in the north in TA 1974, when his forces captured Fornost Erain, the capital of Arthedain. With its capture, the final kingdom collapsed, and with it, the last remnants of the lost realm of Arnor were destroyed. The Witch-king gladly took his seat of power in the newly captured Fornost. But his glory did not last long, for in TA 1975, general Eärnur of Gondor landed at the harbours of the Grey Havens, leading an army of Gondor. His army was joined by the Elves of Lindon and the remnant of the northern Dúnedain and marched on the Witch-king. They did not meet the Witch-king at Fornost, but on the plains west of it toward Lake Evendim, home of the ancient kings of Arnor, Annúminas. The battle would forever be known as the Battle of Fornost. Eärnur's Dúnedain army was later joined in the mists of battle by Glorfindel and his Elven army from Rivendell. The Witch-king revealed himself and challenged Eärnur. As Eärnur attempted to attack, his horse was overwhelmed with fear of the Nazgûl lord and bucked. The Witch-king, taunting Eärnur, fled the battlefield. When Eärnur attempted to follow, Glorfindel stopped him with a warning that would become prophetic in the future: "Do not pursue him! He will not return to these lands. Far off yet is his doom, and not by the hand of man shall he fall." The Witch-king, having destroyed the North-kingdom, fled the North. Angmar was left leaderless and soon collapsed. He was killed in the Battle of the Pelennor Fields by Meriadoc Brandybuck and Éowyn niece of Theóden  at the end of the War thus fullfilling the prophecy of Glorfindel.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_MEC_SNOW_TROLL">
			<Text>Snow Troll</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_UNITS_MEDIEVAL_MEC_SNOW_TROLL">
			<Text>Snow trolls are one of several troll species. They are native to the frozen northern cold wastelands of Angmar. Invented by the designers of the The Rise of the Witch-king, the expansion pack to The Lord of the Rings: The Battle for Middle-earth II, Snow-trolls cannot be considered canonical to Tolkien's works, but the Trolls who lived in the Coldfells in western Eriador must have been similar to these. Snow-Trolls are smaller than their southern relatives, but they are usually ten feet tall. Their skin and fur color is usually white or light grey and they are rather short for trolls; they also possess short and powerful legs to carry them long distances. They are exceptionally fast compared to other troll species, fast enough to keep up with horses and can even briefly outpace them if need be.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_MEC_SNOW_TROLL_STRATEGY">
			<Text>
				The Snow Troll is the primary mobile unit of the Angmar Kingdom. They replace the Knight, but are much different. The are stronger than the knight, but require more production to build then the knigt. The Cave Troll upgrades to the Landship instead of Cavalry. The Snow Troll does not require horses. The Snow Troll comes with a promotion named after itself that gives +25% Attack while in Snow or Tunda Tiles. The Promotion is lost with upgrading the unit. 
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_HELP_MEC_SNOW_TROLL">
			<Text>Replaces the Knight. Stonger in general and even better in Snow or Tundra Tiles.</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_MEC_GUNDABAD_ORC">
			<Text>Gundabad Orc</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_UNITS_ANTIQUITY_MEC_GUNDABAD_ORC">
			<Text>The Gundabad Orcs are Orcs inhabiting Mount Gundabad. They attacked the mountain and took it from the Dwarves of Durin when they had dwelt there. They were the servants of the Witch-king of Angmar before they had seized Gundabad. Some time during the Second Age, the orcs that had survived the destruction of Angband were forced to wander the Northern Waste and find a new home. This was when they attacked the mountain and took it from the Dwarves. In the Third Age, the Orcs of Angmar officially stated Gundabad as their capital which angered the Dwarves greatly. Gundabad remained an Orc stronghold, until it was cleared of orcs in TA 2799, after the War of the Dwarves and Orcs. However, small groups of orcs must have returned and fortified it anew during the events of The Hobbit, menacing Wilderland once again. It was from here that the Goblins present at the Battle of the Five Armies came from in their marching numbers. Their leader, Bolg, son of Azog, was the supreme commander of the orcs from Mount Gundabad and presumably the northern Misty Mountains and was killed by Beorn, the skin-changer. It is unknown what became of the orcs after that or who their leader was, but some say they eventually left Gundabad and settled in the Misty Mountains. The Gundabad Orcs had appearance similar to that of the Orcs of Mordor, the footsoldiers of the Dark Lord Sauron. They had dark skin, fangs, claws, and a small amount of hair. They wore armor of brown and white fur coats threaded with various beast's teeth and sharp shields bearing the Iron Crown. They, like many orcs, used long sharp swords called Scimitars with which they impaled and slashed their victims.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_MEC_GUNDABAD_ORC_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Gundabad Orc is a powerful standard melee unit during the Classical Era. The Gundbad Orc has the Charge Promotion and is therefore +25% better at attacking wounded enemies.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_HELP_MEC_GUNDABAD_ORC">
			<Text>Replaces the Swordsman. +2 CS and Starts with the Charge Promotion</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_MEC_LORD_OF_THE_NAZGUL">
			<Text>Raze cities at double speed. Melee units can Pillage Tiles without using a movement point. Melee units receive Siege Tools, a special promotion that grants +25% [ICON_STRENGTH] attack against Cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_MEC_LORD_OF_THE_NAZGUL_SHORT">
			<Text>Lord of the Nazgul</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MEC_WITCH_KING_NAME">
			<Text>Witch King</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MEC_WITCH_KING_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Lord of Angmar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MEC_WITCH_KING_LIVED">
			<Text>TA1300-TA3019</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MEC_WITCH_KING_DEFEATED_%">
			<Text>Ahhh. My hour has ended. I yield and kneel before your might.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MEC_WITCH_KING_FIRSTGREETING_%">
			<Text>My hour has come. The darkness shall triumph and victory shall be mine. Nothing will remain but ashess and dust. All shall kneel before me.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_ROGASH">
			<Text>Rogash</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_MORGOMIR">
			<Text>Morgomir</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_HWALDAR">
			<Text>Hwaldar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_MAKOARE">
			<Text>Makoare</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_BREOSAL">
			<Text>Breosal</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_ADHARGAL">
			<Text>Adhargal</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_GRISGART">
			<Text>Grisgart</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_MORDRED">
			<Text>Mordred</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_KARSH">
			<Text>Karsh</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_MEC_SNOW_TROLL">
			<Text>Snow Troll</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_MEC_SNOW_TROLL_HELP">
			<Text>+25 Attack in Snow and Tundra</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_MEC_SIEGE_TOOLS">
			<Text>Siege Tools</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_MEC_SIEGE_TOOLS_HELP">
			<Text>+25 Attack against Cities</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>	
