<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>
  <Leaders>
    <Row>
      <Type>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</Type>
      <Description>TXT_KEY_LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</Description>
      <Civilopedia>TXT_KEY_LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS_PEDIA</Civilopedia>
      <CivilopediaTag>TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SOBERNIESANDERS</CivilopediaTag>
      <ArtDefineTag>VT Scene.xml</ArtDefineTag>
      <VictoryCompetitiveness>10</VictoryCompetitiveness>
      <WonderCompetitiveness>2</WonderCompetitiveness>
      <MinorCivCompetitiveness>10</MinorCivCompetitiveness>
      <Boldness>10</Boldness>
      <DiploBalance>10</DiploBalance>
      <WarmongerHate>10</WarmongerHate>
      <WorkAgainstWillingness>2</WorkAgainstWillingness>
      <WorkWithWillingness>10</WorkWithWillingness>
      <DenounceWillingness>8</DenounceWillingness>
      <DoFWillingness>10</DoFWillingness>
      <Loyalty>10</Loyalty>
      <Neediness>2</Neediness>
      <Forgiveness>4</Forgiveness>
      <Chattiness>7</Chattiness>
      <Meanness>1</Meanness>
      <PortraitIndex>0</PortraitIndex>
      <IconAtlas>VT_COLOR_ATLAS_SO</IconAtlas>
    </Row>
  </Leaders>

  <Leader_MajorCivApproachBiases>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <MajorCivApproachType>MAJOR_CIV_APPROACH_WAR</MajorCivApproachType>
      <Bias>1</Bias>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <MajorCivApproachType>MAJOR_CIV_APPROACH_HOSTILE</MajorCivApproachType>
      <Bias>1</Bias>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <MajorCivApproachType>MAJOR_CIV_APPROACH_DECEPTIVE</MajorCivApproachType>
      <Bias>5</Bias>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <MajorCivApproachType>MAJOR_CIV_APPROACH_GUARDED</MajorCivApproachType>
      <Bias>4</Bias>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <MajorCivApproachType>MAJOR_CIV_APPROACH_AFRAID</MajorCivApproachType>
      <Bias>10</Bias>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <MajorCivApproachType>MAJOR_CIV_APPROACH_FRIENDLY</MajorCivApproachType>
      <Bias>10</Bias>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <MajorCivApproachType>MAJOR_CIV_APPROACH_NEUTRAL</MajorCivApproachType>
      <Bias>10</Bias>
    </Row>
  </Leader_MajorCivApproachBiases>
  <Leader_MinorCivApproachBiases>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <MinorCivApproachType>MINOR_CIV_APPROACH_IGNORE</MinorCivApproachType>
      <Bias>5</Bias>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <MinorCivApproachType>MINOR_CIV_APPROACH_FRIENDLY</MinorCivApproachType>
      <Bias>9</Bias>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <MinorCivApproachType>MINOR_CIV_APPROACH_PROTECTIVE</MinorCivApproachType>
      <Bias>9</Bias>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <MinorCivApproachType>MINOR_CIV_APPROACH_CONQUEST</MinorCivApproachType>
      <Bias>1</Bias>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <MinorCivApproachType>MINOR_CIV_APPROACH_BULLY</MinorCivApproachType>
      <Bias>1</Bias>
    </Row>
  </Leader_MinorCivApproachBiases>
  <Leader_Flavors>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_OFFENSE</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>8</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_DEFENSE</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>8</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_CITY_DEFENSE</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>8</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_MILITARY_TRAINING</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>9</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_RECON</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>10</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_RANGED</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>10</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_MOBILE</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>5</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_NAVAL</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>2</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_NAVAL_RECON</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>2</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_NAVAL_GROWTH</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>2</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_NAVAL_TILE_IMPROVEMENT</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>2</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_AIR</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>10</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_EXPANSION</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>2</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_GROWTH</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>5</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_TILE_IMPROVEMENT</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>5</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_INFRASTRUCTURE</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>5</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_PRODUCTION</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>10</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_GOLD</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>8</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_SCIENCE</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>10</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_CULTURE</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>6</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_HAPPINESS</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>10</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_GREAT_PEOPLE</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>2</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_WONDER</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>2</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_RELIGION</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>1</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_DIPLOMACY</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>10</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_SPACESHIP</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>10</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_WATER_CONNECTION</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>2</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_NUKE</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>1</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_USE_NUKE</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>1</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_ESPIONAGE</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>10</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_ANTIAIR</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>5</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_AIR_CARRIER</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>6</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_I_LAND_TRADE_ROUTE</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>7</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_I_SEA_TRADE_ROUTE</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>7</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_ARCHAEOLOGY</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>8</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_I_TRADE_ORIGIN</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>8</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_I_TRADE_DESTINATION</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>8</Flavor>
    </Row>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <FlavorType>FLAVOR_AIRLIFT</FlavorType>
      <Flavor>8</Flavor>
    </Row>
  </Leader_Flavors>
  <Leader_Traits>
    <Row>
      <LeaderType>LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS</LeaderType>
      <TraitType>TRAIT_GREENMOUNTAINPRIDE</TraitType>
    </Row>
  </Leader_Traits>

  <Language_en_US>
    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS">
      <Text>Bernie Sanders</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SOBERNIESANDERS_PEDIA">
      <Text><!-- Add Civilopedia text here --></Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SOBERNIESANDERS_FACT_1">
      <Text>Sanders' Michigan primary victory in March 2016 is considered to be one of the greatest upsets in modern political history. He won 50 to 48, despite late polls showing he was trailing Clinton at least 20 percentage points.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The only time such an egregious polling error was recorded came during the 1984 Democratic primary, when polls showed Walter Mondale leading Gary Hart by 17 percentage points. Hart actually won Michigan by more than nine points.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Sanders' shocking win was a testament that his liberal populist message could resonate within a diverse state such as Michigan and beyond. It was also a huge psychological blow to Clinton's campaign, which had hoped to seal her nomination with ease.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SOBERNIESANDERS_HEADING_1">
      <Text>Summary</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SOBERNIESANDERS_HEADING_2">
      <Text>Early Life and Education</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SOBERNIESANDERS_HEADING_3">
      <Text>Early Political Career</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SOBERNIESANDERS_HEADING_4">
      <Text>Senatorship</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SOBERNIESANDERS_HEADING_5">
      <Text>General Election of 2016</Text>
    </Row>
	  <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SOBERNIESANDERS_HEADING_6">
		  <Text>General Election of 2020</Text>
	  </Row>
	  <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SOBERNIESANDERS_HEADING_7">
		  <Text>Family and Personal Life</Text>
	  </Row>
    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SOBERNIESANDERS_LIVED">
      <Text>1941 AD - Present</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SOBERNIESANDERS_NAME">
      <Text>Bernie Sanders</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SOBERNIESANDERS_SUBTITLE">
      <Text>Leader of Vermont</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SOBERNIESANDERS_TEXT_1">
      <Text>Vermont Senator and former presidential candidate Bernie Sanders is America's longest-serving independent politician in Congress. Born in 1941, politician Bernie Sanders started out his political career as the mayor of Burlington, Vermont, serving four terms as the leader of the state's biggest city from 1981 to 1989. He then moved on to the national political arena by winning a seat in the House of Representatives, distinguishing himself as one of the country's few independent legislators. Sanders won election to the U.S. Senate in 2006 and was reelected in 2012. He announced his plans to run for the Democratic presidential nomination in 2015, ultimately sparking a huge progressive movement, before conceding the nomination to Hillary Clinton. The Vermont senator launched another presidential campaign in 2019, but again came up short in his bid for the Democratic nomination. </Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SOBERNIESANDERS_TEXT_2">
      <Text>Independent politician Bernie Sanders was born on September 8, 1941, in New York. He grew up in Brooklyn as the youngest of two sons of Jewish immigrants from Poland. His father worked as a paint salesman. As part of a struggling working-class family, Sanders recognized early on America's economic disparity. As he told the Guardian newspaper, "I saw unfairness. That was the major inspiration in my politics." Sanders also counts American socialist leader Eugene V. Debs as an important influence.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Sanders attended Brooklyn's James Madison High School and then went on to Brooklyn College. After a year there, he transferred to the University of Chicago. Sanders became involved in the Civil Rights Movement during his university days. As a member of the Congress of Racial Equality (CORE), Sanders participated in a sit-in against the segregation of off-campus housing in 1962. He also served as an organizer for the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee. In 1963 he participated in the March on Washington.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]After finishing college in 1964 with a degree in political science, Sanders lived on a kibbutz in Israel before settling in Vermont. He worked a number of jobs, including filmmaker, freelance writer, psychiatric aide and teacher for low-income children through Head Start, while his interest in politics grew.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SOBERNIESANDERS_TEXT_3">
      <Text>In 1981, Sanders was elected mayor of Burlington, Vermont, by only 12 votes. Sanders was able to achieve this win with the support of the Progressive Coalition, a grassroots organization. He was reelected three more times, proving that the self-described "democratic socialist" had staying power.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Known for his rumpled clothes and untamed mane, Sanders made an unlikely candidate for national office, but this political underdog scored a 1990 win for a seat in the U.S. House of Representatives. As an independent, Sanders found himself facing a dilemma. He had to find political allies to advance his issues and legislation. As Sanders explained to The Progressive, he considered working with the Republicans to be "unthinkable," but he did caucus with the Democrats despite "a lot of opposition among conservative Democrats to my being in that caucus."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Outspoken on the issues, Sanders criticized both parties whenever he felt they were in the wrong. He was a vocal opponent of the Iraq War, concerned about the social and financial impact that the conflict could cause. In an address to the House, he said "As a caring Nation, we should do everything we can to prevent the horrible suffering that a war will cause." Sanders also questioned the timing of military action "at a time when this country has a $6 trillion national debt and a growing deficit."</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SOBERNIESANDERS_TEXT_4">
      <Text>Sanders sought to switch to the Senate in 2006, running against Republican businessman Richard Tarrant. He managed to win despite his opponent's significant advantage in funding: Tarrant spent $7 million of his own personal wealth in this election battle.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In 2010, Sanders made the news with his more than eight-hour-long filibuster against the extension of George W. Bush-era tax cuts for the wealthy. He felt that this legislation was "a very bad tax agreement" between the president and Republican legislators, he later wrote in the introduction of The Speech: A Historic Filibuster on Corporate Greed and the Decline of Our Middle Class. Sanders ended his time on the Senate floor with a plea to his legislative colleagues to come up with "a better proposal which better reflects the needs of the middle class and working families of our country and to me, most importantly, the children of our country," according to a Washington Post article.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]During his time in the Senate, Sanders has served on several committees on issues important to him. He is a member of the Committee on Budget; the Committee on Health, Education, Labor and Pensions; the Committee on Veterans Affairs and the Joint Economic Committee. Sanders also champions campaign reform and advocates for an amendment to overturn the Supreme Court decision on Citizens United.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Sanders has advocated for expanding voting rights and opposed the Supreme Court decision to disband part of the landmark Voting Rights Act. He is also an advocate for universal single-payer health care system. Driven by his sense of protecting the environment, addressing climate change and interest in renewable energy, Sanders is a member of the U.S. Senate Committee on Environment &#38; Public Works and the Energy &#38; Natural Resources Committee.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SOBERNIESANDERS_TEXT_5">
      <Text>In April 2015, Sanders announced that he was seeking the presidential nomination for the Democratic Party. This longtime independent made the party switch largely out of political necessity. Sanders' platform focused on issues of inequality in the United States. Economically, he favored tax reform to increase rates for the wealthy, greater governmental oversight of Wall Street and balancing the disparity between wages for men and women. He also advocated for a state-administered health care system, more-affordable higher education — including tuition-free public colleges and universities — and an expansion of the Social Security, Medicare and Medicaid systems. A social liberal, he supported same-sex marriage and pro-choice policy.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Staying true to his principles, Sanders relied almost solely on small individual donations rather than Super PACs to run his presidential primary race. To the surprise of many and admittedly, to Sanders himself, he made an unprecedented mark on campaign fundraising in American politics. In December 2015, Time magazine wrote, "Bernie Sanders has broken the fundraising record for most contributions at this point in a presidential campaign," even surpassing President Obama's fundraising record for his 2011 (sic) reelection bid.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Sanders made more headlines as the first presidential candidate — and the only Jewish one — in the 2016 race to abstain from attending the AIPAC conference, an annual pro-Israel lobbying event.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]As Sanders' campaign came to a close, along with the reality that the odds were stacked against him, the senator used his political clout to advance the DNC platform before putting his full support behind Clinton.</Text>
    </Row>
	  <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SOBERNIESANDERS_TEXT_6">
		  <Text>After Trump's stunning 2016 Election Day win over Clinton, Sanders vowed he would continue to stand up to the new president when necessary.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]One year later, news outlets floated the idea that Sanders was positioning himself for another run in 2020. Among the evidence cited, it was noted he was developing a series of foreign policy speeches with Bill Clinton's former defense secretary, and had the position of "outreach chairman" created for him by Senate Minority Leader Chuck Schumer, a role he was using to establish relationships with entrenched Democratic Party bigwigs.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Sanders formally announced his bid for president in February 2019, joining a crowded field that already included Democratic stars Kamala Harris, Cory Booker and Kirsten Gillibrand.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Sanders fared well in the polls through the first few primary debates, before being hospitalized and treated for artery blockage in early October. Recovering in time to make the stage for the fourth debate, he received a boost with the news he would draw the endorsements of New York Congresswoman Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez and two fellow members of the House "Squad," Ilhan Omar of Minnesota and Rashida Tlaib of Michigan.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]When it came time to start counting delegates in early 2020, Sanders finished just behind upstart Pete Buttigieg in the controversial Iowa caucuses, and followed with a win in New Hampshire to emerge as the frontrunner for the Democratic nomination.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]However, Joe Biden soon took a commanding lead in the primaries, forcing Sanders to play catch-up as the other candidates dropped out and threw their support behind the former vice president. Unlike in 2016, when he remained in the race even as it became clear that Clinton would claim the nomination, Sanders ended his campaign on April 8, 2020.</Text>
	  </Row>
	  <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SOBERNIESANDERS_TEXT_7">
		  <Text>In 1964 Sanders married his college sweetheart Deborah Shiling, but the couple divorced two years later. In 1968 he met Susan Mott and the two had a son, Levi, in 1969.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Sanders met his second wife, Jane O'Meara, right before becoming mayor of Burlington in 1981. A long-time educator, O'Meara would eventually become president of Burlington College. The two married in 1988. O'Meara has three children from a previous marriage.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Sanders' older brother, Larry, is a British academic and politician, who is currently the Health Spokesperson for the leftist Green Party of England and Wales.</Text>
	  </Row>
    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SOBERNIESANDERS_TITLES_1">
      <Text>Senator from Vermont[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Representative from Vermont</Text>
    </Row>
  </Language_en_US>
</GameData>
