<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
	  
<GameData>  
	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV_MEC_HOBBITS_DESC">
			<Text>Hobbits of the Shire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV_MEC_HOBBITS_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Hobbits</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV_MEC_HOBBITS_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Hobbit</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV5_MEC_HOBBITS_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Bandobras Took was the second son of Thain Isumbras III, and the Great-Grand-Uncle of Bilbo Baggins. He was born in TA 2704. Bandobras is noteworthy among Hobbits for his exceptionally large stature, being four feet, five inches tall and able to ride a horse. He was the tallest Hobbit on record until the Ent-draughts taken by Meriadoc Brandybuck and Peregrin Took made them the tallest Hobbits in the history of the Shire. Bandobras also gained fame for leading the Hobbits at the Battle of Greenfields in TA 2747 when goblins from Mount Gram in the Misty Mountains invaded the Northfarthing. According to the narrative in the book The Hobbit, during the battle Bandobras charged the ranks of the goblins of Mount Gram and with a wooden club knocked the goblin chieftain Golfimbul's head clean off, sending it sailing a hundred yards through the air and down a rabbit-hole, thus (according to Tolkien's novel The Hobbit) winning the battle and inventing the game of Golf at the same time. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE] Bandobras, "Bullroarer", the Hobbits of the Shire have called upon your bravery once more. You must ride once again and vanquish the evils of that the Outsiders have brought to your lands. The fate of the Hobbits is in your hands. Can you build a civilization that will stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV_MEC_HOBBITS_PEDIA">
			<Text>Hobbits, also known as Halflings, were an ancient mortal race. Although their exact origins are unknown, they were initially found in the northern parts of Middle-earth and below the Vales of Anduin. At the beginning of the Third Age, Hobbits moved north and west. Most of their race eventually founded the land of the Shire in about the year TA 1601. Most Hobbits enjoyed farming, food, ales, parties and the giving and receiving of presents. They were usually friendly and happy-go-lucky, although they were often shy of Men. Hobbits prefer a quiet, normal, and peaceful life. Hobbits, particularly those of the Shire are very insular and are suspicious of other people from other places and anything that disturbs the peace. Hobbits refer to people outside the Shire as Outsiders, being a very broad term, were simply those foreign to any region. Just as hobbits consider themselves to be right and proper when compared to the outsiders, others consider the hobbits to be the strange, little folk.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV5_MEC_HOBBITS">
			<Text>Hobbits of the Shire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_MICHEL_DELVING">
			<Text>Michel Delving</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_TUCKBOROUGH">
			<Text>Tuckborough</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_HOBBITON">
			<Text>Hobbiton</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_FROGMORTON">
			<Text>Frogmorton</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_THE_SHIRE">
			<Text>The Shire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_GREENFIELDS">
			<Text>Greenfields</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_OATBARTON">
			<Text>Oatbarton</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_CRICKHOLLOW">
			<Text>Crickhollow</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_BUCKLAND">
			<Text>Buckland</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_BRANDYWINE">
			<Text>Brandywine</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_BYWATER">
			<Text>Bywater</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_THE_YALE">
			<Text>The Yale</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_SUZA">
			<Text>Suza</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_TOOKLAND">
			<Text>Tookland</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_EASTMARCH">
			<Text>Eastmarch</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_LONG_CLEEVE">
			<Text>Long Cleeve</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_NEEDLEHOLE">
			<Text>Needlehole</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_TIGHFIELD">
			<Text>Tighfield</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_GAMWICH">
			<Text>Gamwich</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_TOOKBANK">
			<Text>Tookbank</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_WHITWELL">
			<Text>Whitwell</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_HARDBOTTLE">
			<Text>Hardbottle</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_SACKVILLE">
			<Text>Sackville</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_LONGBOTTOM">
			<Text>Longbottom</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_STOCK">
			<Text>Stock</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_BROCKENBORINGS">
			<Text>Brockenborings</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_BINDBALE">
			<Text>Bindbale</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_RUSHOCK">
			<Text>Rushock</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_LITTLE_DELVING">
			<Text>Little Delving</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_GREENHOLM">
			<Text>Greenholm</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_RUSHY">
			<Text>Rushy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_DEEPHOLLOW">
			<Text>Deephollow</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_WILLOWBOTTOM">
			<Text>Willowbottom</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_THISTLE_BROOK">
			<Text>Thistle Brook</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_THE_WARDEN">
			<Text>The Warden</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_EMYN_BERAID">
			<Text>Emyn Beraid</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_BUCKLEBURY">
			<Text>Bucklebury</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_BAG_END">
			<Text>Bag End</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_NOBOTTLE">
			<Text>Nobottle</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_WAYMEET">
			<Text>Waymeet</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_PINCUP">
			<Text>Pincup</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MEC_BANDOBRAS">
			<Text>Bandobras</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MEC_BANDOBRAS_PEDIA">
			<Text>Bandobras Took</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MEC_BANDOBRAS">
			<Text>Bandobras Took was the second son of Thain Isumbras III, and the Great-Grand-Uncle of Bilbo Baggins. He was born in TA 2704. Bandobras is noteworthy among Hobbits for his exceptionally large stature, being four feet, five inches tall and able to ride a horse. He was the tallest Hobbit on record until the Ent-draughts taken by Meriadoc Brandybuck and Peregrin Took made them the tallest Hobbits in the history of the Shire. Bandobras also gained fame for leading the Hobbits at the Battle of Greenfields in TA 2747 when goblins from Mount Gram in the Misty Mountains invaded the Northfarthing. According to the narrative in the book The Hobbit, during the battle Bandobras charged the ranks of the goblins of Mount Gram and with a wooden club knocked the goblin chieftain Golfimbul's head clean off, sending it sailing a hundred yards through the air and down a rabbit-hole, thus (according to Tolkien's novel The Hobbit) winning the battle and inventing the game of Golf at the same time. Bandobras was given the nickname "Bullroarer". From him were descended the North-tooks of Long Cleeve, where Peregrin Took's wife Diamond of Long Cleeve came from. Bandobras died in TA 2806.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_MEC_SHIRRIFF">
			<Text>Shirriff</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_UNITS_ANTIQUITY_MEC_SHIRRIFF">
			<Text>The Shirriffs, also known as the Watch, were the sole form of law enforcement in the Shire, and the closest thing to a form of defense or deterrent that the Shire possessed.The position of Shirriff was a voluntary honor. There were a total of twelve Shirriffs, three for each Farthing, though more could be called up in time of need (as happened around TA 3001). The only thing that differentiated Shirriffs from other Hobbits was a feather they were given to wear in their hats. The Shirriffs carried no arms or armament of any sort and wore no uniform. The Shirriffs were headed by the First Shirriff which was answerable to the Mayor of Michel Delving. The Shirriffs were probably based on some form of ancient tradition, possibly dating back to the Kingdom of Arnor. But as the Shire was a peaceful place, their only purpose was protecting the Shire from trespassers. They were also possibly responsible for deputizing hobbits into the Bounders service who patrolled the borders.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_MEC_SHIRRIFF_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Shirriff is a much weaker unit than the warrior which it replaces. The Shirriffs best attribute is the unique free promotion of Defend the Shire which gives +50% CS in Friendly Territory. This promotion stays with the Shirriff when its upgraded. So the best strategy with the Shirriff is to give him a weapon by upgrading him.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_HELP_MEC_SHIRRIFF">
			<Text>Very weak early game defensive unit. Replaces the warrior.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENTS_MEC_HOBBIT_HOLE">
			<Text>Hobbit Hole</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENTS_MEC_HOBBIT_HOLE_CIV_PEDIA">
			<Text>Hobbit-holes, otherwise called Smials, were the preferred dwellings of Hobbits in the Shire, the ancient mortal race inhabiting Middle-earth. They were holes dug into the hill side, usually having a minimum of one round window and front door and sometimes back door. It was the primarily wealthy families of Hobbits built Smials, spacious and luxurious tunnels, a souped up version of a Hobbit-hole. Brandy Hall is an example of a Smial and had three front doors, many side doors and around one hundred windows. Bag End, the home of Bilbo Baggins and later Sackville-Bagginses and then Sam Gamgee, could be called a Smial, as it was an expansive Hobbit-hole with many windows; a large circular green front and back door, and a large number of rooms; as well as the famously renowned pantries which supplied food for many a party or celebration. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE] Must be built on a hill. The Hobbit Hole provides +1[ICON_FOOD] food. When Civil Service is discovered and with access to fresh water they provide +1[ICON_FOOD] food. Without access to fresh water, when Fertilizer is discovered they provide +1[ICON_FOOD] food. When Architecture is discovered they provide +2 [ICON_CULTURE] culture</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENTS_MEC_HOBBIT_HOLE_HELP">
			<Text>Must be built on a hill. The Hobbit Hole provides +1[ICON_FOOD] food. When Civil Service is discovered and with access to fresh water they provide +1[ICON_FOOD] food. Without access to fresh water, when Fertilizer is discovered they provide +1[ICON_FOOD] food. When Architecture is discovered they provide +2 [ICON_CULTURE] culture</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILD_MEC_HOBBIT_HOLE">
			<Text>Construct a Hobbit Hole</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_MEC_SWEET_GALENAS">
			<Text>After discovering Calendar the next 3 cities founded each provide 2 unique Luxury Resources (and can never be razed). Also [ICON_HAPPINESS_4] Unhappiness from number of cities increases by 34%.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_MEC_SWEET_GALENAS_SHORT">
			<Text>Sweet Galenas</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MEC_BANDOBRAS_NAME">
			<Text>Bradobras Took</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MEC_BANDOBRAS_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Bullroarer</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MEC_BANDOBRAS_LIVED">
			<Text>TA2701-TA2806</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MEC_BANDOBRAS_DEFEATED_%">
			<Text>On this day the Hobbits are defeated, but do not consider this a victory. For it is not a true victory when you conquer those too small to defend themselves.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MEC_BANDOBRAS_FIRSTGREETING_%">
			<Text>Outsider! What brings you to the Shire?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_BILBO">
			<Text>Bilbo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_FRODO">
			<Text>Frodo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_PEREGRIN">
			<Text>Peregrin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_SAMWISE">
			<Text>Samwise</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_ROSIE">
			<Text>Rosie</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_TOBOLD">
			<Text>Tobold</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_ISENGRIM">
			<Text>Isengrim</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_ELANOR">
			<Text>Elanor</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_MERIADOC">
			<Text>Meriadoc</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_MEC_DEFEND_THE_SHIRE">
			<Text>Defend the Shire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_MEC_DEFEND_THE_SHIRE_HELP">
			<Text>+25% CS in Friendly Territory</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RESOURCE_MEC_GALENAS">
			<Text>Galenas</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_RESOURCE_MEC_GALENAS">
			<Text>The name that the Dunedain gave to Halfling's Leaf.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RESOURCE_MEC_GALENAS_HELP">
			<Text>Galenas provides Happiness</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RESOURCE_MEC_LONGBOTTOM_LEAF">
			<Text>Longbottom Leaf</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_RESOURCE_MEC_LONGBOTTOM_LEAF">
			<Text>Longbottom was a region in the shire where Halfling's Leaf was grown.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RESOURCE_MEC_LONGBOTTOM_LEAF_HELP">
			<Text>Longbottom Leaf provides Happiness</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RESOURCE_MEC_OLD_TOBY">
			<Text>Old Toby</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_RESOURCE_MEC_OLD_TOBY">
			<Text>Named after Tobold Hornblower, the Hobbit who first introduced Halfling's Leaf to the Hobbits of the Shire.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RESOURCE_MEC_OLD_TOBY_HELP">
			<Text>Old Toby provides Happiness</Text>
		</Row>
		
		
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>	
