<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 7/8/2022 8:25:08 PM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_MATHALX_INAZUMA_DESC">
			<Text>Inazuma</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_MATHALX_INAZUMA_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Inazuma</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_MATHALX_INAZUMA_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_MATHALX_INAZUMA_TEXT_1">
			<Text>
				Inazuma is one of the states that appear in Genshin Impact. Based on the Edo Shogunate Japan, Inazuma is situated on an archipelago some distance away from the main Teyvat continent. Inazuma is portrayed as in a state of chaos and its populace fairly negatively: its people have a degree of xenophobia and it is troubled by problems such as famine and corruption, and it also has to deal with the Watatsumi rebels under Kokomi.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Inazuma's troubles are compounded by Raiden Shogun's attitude and policies: while the Vision Hunt Decree was not of Raiden Shogun's initiative but rather a result of the collusion between the Fatui and the Commissions, the problem caused by the Vision Hunt and the Sakoku (the latter initiated by Raiden Shogun) was not accounted by the Shogun due to both deception from the Fatui and the Commission as well as Shogun's own motives regarding eternity, resulting in the Shogun doing little to correct the situation and resulting in the state of suffering.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_MATHALX_INAZUMA_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Strategy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_MATHALX_INAZUMA_TEXT_2">
			<Text>
				Inazuma is a civilization that requires a great deal of thought when it comes to taking wonders, yet wonders are central to it. Inazuma builds its first World Wonder per era 50% faster, so even with Civ IV Traits enabled it can compete with civilizations with the Industrious trait if considering only the first wonder. Not only that, each wonder claimed by this effect has its effect doubled, allowing Inazuma to turn the tide of the game with a powerful wonder acquisition. However, Inazuma pays for this powerful potential with rising social policy cost, making it difficult to adopt later era policies such as Rationalism and Ideology tenents.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_MATHALX_INAZUMA">
			<Text>Inazuma</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_MATHALX_INAZUMA_TITLE">
			<Text>Inazuma</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_MATHALX_INAZUMA_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Inazuma</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_MATHALX_PURE_LAND_ONE_MIND">
			<Text>First World Wonder per era is attempted with a 50% [ICON_PRODUCTION] bonus, and a successful attempt results in double its effects, but at cost of raising the cost of future social policies by 10%.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_MATHALX_PURE_LAND_ONE_MIND_SHORT">
			<Text>Pure Land of One Mind</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_MATHALX_INAZUMA_DOM">
			<Text>
				Inazuma's people look to you for guidance and protection, great Raiden Shogun! You are the war god and thunder god of Inazuma, assigned the task of protecting it from outside threats. You sought to shape Inazuma into a land of eternity to shelter its people from the sadness of loss, but the conspiracy of the Fatui and the corruption of the Commissions led you to be played and brought Inazuma a dark age of famine, economic stagnation, and the Vision Hunt Decree. While the efforts of the traveler and the Yashiro Commission helped you to see the truth and think harder about your convictions, Inazuma still needed time to recoverNEWLINE][NEWLINE]Mighty Raiden Shogun, a new world awaits the birth of a new Inazuma, a world without the Fatui to bring it suffering. Will you stick to your original vision and bring forth eternity, or apply the teachings you've learned with the traveler to build a better Inazuma? Will you make Inazuma a paradise for its people who will never have to fear pain? Can you build a civilization that will stand the test of time?
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MATHALX_RAIDEN_SHOGUN_PEDIA">
			<Text>
				TBA
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MATHALX_RAIDEN_SHOGUN_LIVED">
			<Text>?/6/26-</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MATHALX_RAIDEN_SHOGUN_NAME">
			<Text>Raiden Shogun</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MATHALX_RAIDEN_SHOGUN">
			<Text>Raiden Shogun</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MATHALX_RAIDEN_SHOGUN_CIV_IV">
			<Text>Raiden Shogun [ICON_PEACE][ICON_HAPPINESS_1]</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MATHALX_RAIDEN_SHOGUN_CIV_IV_PON">
			<Text>Raiden Shogun [ICON_PEACE][ICON_CAPITAL]</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MATHALX_RAIDEN_SHOGUN_HEADING_1">
			<Text>Overview</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MATHALX_RAIDEN_SHOGUN_TEXT_1">
			<Text>
				Raiden Shogun is a character who appears in Genshin Impact, and is the ruler of Inazuma, a state situated in an archipelago some distance away from mainland Teyvat.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Spoiler Alert[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Raiden Shogun is a puppet created by Raiden Ei, who shaped the Shogun in her image. Ei purposefully makde Shogun difficult to reprogram as to make her resistant to change, which unfortunately compounded to the suffering of Inazuma.
			</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MATHALX_RAIDEN_SHOGUN_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Judgment</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MATHALX_RAIDEN_SHOGUN_TEXT_2">
			<Text>
				While there were outside influences such as the Fatui conspiracy and a circumstance that led to the set of belief, Raiden Shogun is seen as a poor ruler who drove Inazuma into a state of crisis. The rigid adherence to the idea of eternity resulted in her refusal to accept change and led to the Sakoku decree that crippled Inazuma's trade, and while the Shogun did not initiate the Vision Hunt Decree she let it (and the repression that it caused) continue. Not only that, the Shogun had failed to find a diplomatic solution with the Watatsumi rebels which had a bad history with the thunder god.
			</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MATHALX_RAIDEN_SHOGUN_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Shogun of the Inazuma Shogunate</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MATHALX_RAIDEN_SHOGUN_TITLES_1">
			<Text>Raiden Ei</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MATHALX_RAIDEN_SHOGUN_TITLES_2">
			<Text>Guardian of Eternity</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MATHALX_INAZUMA_CITY">
			<Text>Inazuma City</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MATHALX_GRAND_NARUKAMI_SHRINE">
			<Text>Grand Narukami Shrine</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MATHALX_RITOU">
			<Text>Ritou</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MATHALX_KONDA">
			<Text>Konda</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MATHALX_CHINJU">
			<Text>Chinju</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MATHALX_YOUGOU">
			<Text>Yougou</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MATHALX_KUJOU_ENCAMPMENT">
			<Text>Kujou Encampment</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MATHALX_NAZUCHI">
			<Text>Nazuchi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MATHALX_JINREN">
			<Text>Jinren</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MATHALX_MIKAGE_FURNACE">
			<Text>Mikage Furnace</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MATHALX_HIGI">
			<Text>Higi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MATHALX_MUMEI">
			<Text>Mumei</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MATHALX_ARAUMI">
			<Text>Araumi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MATHALX_MUSOUJIN">
			<Text>Musoujin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MATHALX_JAKOTSU">
			<Text>Jakotsu</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_MATHALX_SARA">
			<Text>Sara</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_MATHALX_AYAKA">
			<Text>Ayaka</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_MATHALX_MIKO">
			<Text>Miko</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_MATHALX_YOIMIYA">
			<Text>Yoimiya</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_MATHALX_MASAHITO">
			<Text>Masahito</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_MATHALX_MOMOKA">
			<Text>Momoka</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_MATHALX_THOMA">
			<Text>Thoma</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_MATHALX_KOBAYASHI">
			<Text>Kobayashi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_MATHALX_SASAKI">
			<Text>Sasaki</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MATHALX_COMMISSION">
			<Text>Commission Office</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MATHALX_COMMISSION_TEXT">
			<Text>The Tri-Commission was the executive body created to execute whatever policy that Raiden Shogun decreed. The Tri-Commission consisted of the Kanjou Commission in charge of the finance and managed by the Hiiragi clan, the Tenryou Commission in charge of security and military as well as the enforcement of the Vision Hunt Decree in Kujou clan's care, and the Kamisato clan's Yashiro Commission in charge of religious festivals, culture and crafts.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MATHALX_COMMISSION_HELP">
			<Text>Replaces the Market. Provides [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production, and unlocks the three Commissions from which one can be chosen per city.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Only Inazuma may produce this building.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MATHALX_COMMISSION_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Commission Office is the Inazuman unique building which replaces the Market. It provides production on the Market which is already useful for its gold bonus making it a no-brainer to build, and in addition unlocks one of the Commission to further enhance the city.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MATHALX_COMMISSION_HELP_PON">
			<Text>Replaces the Courthouse. Provides [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production, and unlocks the three Commissions from which one can be chosen per city.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Only Inazuma may produce this building.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MATHALX_COMMISSION_STRATEGY_PON">
			<Text>The Commission Office is the Inazuman unique building which replaces the Courthouse. It provides production which makes it more attractive to build especially after building a Government Complex, and in addition unlocks one of the Commission to further enhance the city.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MATHALX_KANJOU_COMMISSION">
			<Text>Kanjou Commission</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MATHALX_KANJOU_COMMISSION_TEXT">
			<Text>The Kanjou Commission is in charge of the finance and trade, and is tasked with managing the foreign population at Ritou to keep track of their entry to Inazuma. The Hiiragi clan in charge of the commission took advantage of the situation by exploiting the foreign merchants, and its clan leader Hiiragi Shinsuke and a few others colluded with the Fatui to subvert Inazuma. However, the story results in the deposition of Shinsuke, leaving his daughter Chisato in charge who has no ties with the Fatui to restore the Hiiragi clan.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MATHALX_KANJOU_COMMISSION_HELP">
			<Text>+1 [ICON_GOLD] Gold per 4 [ICON_CITIZEN] Citizen in the city. Outgoing [ICON_GOLD] Gold [ICON_INTERNATIONAL_TRADE] Trade Routes generate 2 Gold, while incoming foreign trade routes generate 2 more gold for both parties.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]City must have a Commission Office.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Only Inazuma may produce this building.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MATHALX_TENRYOU_COMMISSION">
			<Text>Tenryou Commission</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MATHALX_TENRYOU_COMMISSION_TEXT">
			<Text>The Tenryou Commission is in charge of security and defense, as well as enforcing the Vision Hunt Decree. However, due to the terrible effects of the Vision Hunt as well as war fatigue, the Tenryou Commission faces a high rate of desertion. This was not helped by the hardline attitude of the clan leader Takayuki, who took the Fatui's suggestion that led to the Vision Hunt Decree and proposed it to the Shogun thinking the Fatui were no threat to the Shogunate. However, Takayuki was an accomplice and compounded his guilt by submitting false reports to the Shogunate. The deception was eventually discovered, and while Takayuki was unharmed in person due to old age and his history of service to the Shogun, he was sentenced to house arrest leaving Masahito as the head of the clan. However, Masahito was bound to his military duty and thus left the clan in charge of his younger brother Kamaji, while the Commission was reformed for a time being to wait for the Kujou Clan to restore itself, with Shogun herself taking some of the duties while the defense of Inazuma City was left to Sara Kujou.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MATHALX_TENRYOU_COMMISSION_HELP">
			<Text>+2 [ICON_HAPPINESS_1] Local Happiness. Military Units trained in the city gains +15 Experience.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]City must have a Commission Office.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Only Inazuma may produce this building.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MATHALX_YASHIRO_COMMISSION">
			<Text>Yashiro Commission</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MATHALX_YASHIRO_COMMISSION_TEXT">
			<Text>The Yashiro Commission is in charge of shrines, festivals, cultural events and craft, and are tasked with assisting the shrines in performing rituals as well as managing and protecting craftsmen. While the heads of clans in charge of other Commissions were colluding with the Fatui, the Kamisato Clan in charge of the Yashiro Commission was the sole exception, with Ayato declining such a proposal. Not only that, their duties made them popular amongst the civilians and their subtle resistance to the Vision Hunt Decree made the Yashiro Commission the most positively portrayed Commission.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MATHALX_YASHIRO_COMMISSION_HELP">
			<Text>Provides an Artist Slot and boosts [ICON_GREAT_PEOPLE] Great People generation by 25%.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]City must have a Commission Office.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Only Inazuma may produce this building.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_MATHALX_DOUSHIN">
			<Text>Doushin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_MATHALX_DOUSHIN_HELP">
			<Text>
				Replaces the Pikeman. Doushin are stronger in friendly territory, and also may strike first with a ranged attack if starting the turn in Inazuman territory.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Only Inazuma may produce this unit.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_MATHALX_DOUSHIN_TEXT">
			<Text>
				Doushin historically meant low-level officials of the Edo Shogunate, and in the context of Inazuma, they are low ranking soldiers higher than Ashigaru but lower than the Yoriki. They are mostly seen patrolling Inazuma City.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_MATHALX_DOUSHIN_STRATEGY">
			<Text>
				Doushin is the Inazuman unique unit replacing the Pikeman. They are stronger in friendly territories, and their defensive capability is augmented by their ability to initiate attack with an ranged attack if starting a turn in Inazuman territory.
			</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_MATHALX_DOUSHIN_STRIKE">
			<Text>Blessing of the Shogun</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_MATHALX_DOUSHIN_STRIKE_HELP">
			<Text>Initiates with an ranged attack before the main melee attack.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GENERIC_MATHALX_INAZUMA_INFLUENTIAL_ON_AI_1">
			<Text>Our people are obsessed with eternity and are meditating... while I am confiscating something from the populace. I fear that the world will succumb to the power of your culture.</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>