<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
	  
<GameData>  
	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV_MEC_GOBLINS_DESC">
			<Text>Goblin Kingdom</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV_MEC_GOBLINS_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Goblins</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV_MEC_GOBLINS_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Goblin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV5_MEC_GOBLINS_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Azog was a powerful Orc who claimed rulership over the abandoned Dwarvish mines of Moria, during the late Third Age. He became the leader of the Goblins of Moria and initiated the War of the Dwarves and Orcs in TA 2790, by beheading King Thrór, who had come to revisit the ruins of the ancient dwarven Kingdom of Moria. At some point he had a son named Bolg. In the following years, Azog was the common enemy of all dwarves, and the war he started had its climax in the Battle of Azanulbizar, where he killed Náin, only to be himself slain by Náin's son Dáin, who would later become King of Durin's Folk. His son, Bolg, inherited the reign in Moria and continued it for decades until his death at the Battle of the Five Armies. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE] Azog the Defiler, the Goblin race calls upon you to reclaim their lands. Will you behead your enemies and declare victory over them? Or will you fail and let the Goblin race decline into nothingness? Can you build a civilization that will stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV_MEC_GOBLINS_PEDIA">
			<Text>Goblins are what Tolkien called the Orcs that Thorin and Company encountered in the book The Hobbit. They lived deep under the Misty Mountains in many strongholds, ever since the War of Wrath in the First Age. In The Hobbit, Tolkien described them as big, ugly creatures, "cruel, wicked, and bad-hearted." Tolkien explained in a note at the start of The Hobbit that he was using English to represent the languages used by the characters, and that goblin (or hobgoblin for the larger kind) was the English translation he was using for the word Orc, which (he wrote) is the hobbits' form of the name for them. Tolkien used the term goblin extensively in The Hobbit, and also occasionally in The Lord of the Rings, as when the Uruk-hai of Isengard are first described: "four goblin-soldiers of greater stature". A clear illustration that Tolkien considered goblins and orcs to be the same thing, the former word merely the English translation of the latter, is that in The Hobbit (the only one of Tolkien's works in which he usually refers to orcs as goblins) Gandalf asks Thorin if he remembers Azog the goblin who killed his grandfather Thror,[1] while in all his other writings Tolkien describes Azog as a "great Orc."</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV5_MEC_GOBLINS">
			<Text>Goblin Kingdom</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_ETTENMOORS">
			<Text>Ettenmoors</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_MOUNT_GUNDABAD">
			<Text>Mount Gundabad</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_MORIA">
			<Text>Moria</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_MISTY_MOUNTAINS">
			<Text>Misty Mountains</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_WITHERED_HEATH">
			<Text>Withered Heath</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_GREY_MOUNTAINS">
			<Text>Grey Mountains</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_URULOKI">
			<Text>Uruloki</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_HIGH_PASS">
			<Text>High Pass</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_DWARROWDELF">
			<Text>Dwarrodelf</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_GOBLIN_TOWN">
			<Text>Goblin-Town</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_GLAURUNG">
			<Text>Glaurung</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_ANCALAGON">
			<Text>Ancalagon</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_SCATHA">
			<Text>Scatha</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_MOUNT_GRAM">
			<Text>Mount Gram</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_TROLLSHAWLS">
			<Text>Trollshawls</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_HOARDALE">
			<Text>Hoardale</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_COLDFELLS">
			<Text>Coldfells</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_RHIMDATH">
			<Text>Rhimdath</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_GREAT_CAVERN">
			<Text>Great Cavern</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MEC_AZOG">
			<Text>Azog</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MEC_AZOG_PEDIA">
			<Text>Azog</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MEC_AZOG">
			<Text>Azog was a powerful Orc who claimed rulership over the abandoned Dwarvish mines of Moria, during the late Third Age. He became the leader of the Goblins of Moria and initiated the War of the Dwarves and Orcs in TA 2790, by beheading King Thrór, who had come to revisit the ruins of the ancient dwarven Kingdom of Moria. At some point he had a son named Bolg. In the following years, Azog was the common enemy of all dwarves, and the war he started had its climax in the Battle of Azanulbizar, where he killed Náin, only to be himself slain by Náin's son Dáin, who would later become King of Durin's Folk. His son, Bolg, inherited the reign in Moria and continued it for decades until his death at the Battle of the Five Armies.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- 
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_GOBLIN_WARRIOR">
			<Text>Goblin Warrior</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_UNITS_ANTIQUITY_GOBLIN_WARRIOR">
			<Text>Goblin Warriors are a breed of Goblins that fight with swords. They have appeared in The Hobbit Video Game and The LOTR: Battle for Middle Earth II video game.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_GOBLIN_WARRIOR_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The goblin warrior is just like the basic warrior except cheaper to produce.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_HELP_GOBLIN_WARRIOR">
			<Text>Cheap basic melee unit. Replaces the warrior.</Text>
		</Row>
		-->
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_MEC_CAVE_TROLL">
			<Text>Cave Troll</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_UNITS_MEDIEVAL_MEC_CAVE_TROLL">
			<Text>
				Cave-trolls are a race of Trolls found within the caves of the Misty Mountains. One of them shows in the Fellowship of the Ring, as the Fellowship passed through Moria - at the battle at the Chamber of Mazarbul. Cave-trolls' heights can range from 11 to 19 feet. They retain dark-yellow skin with tinted blue hues and purple eyes. Their blood is black in color, and very hot. Their hides cannot be pierced by normal swords, and remain hard to pierce even when confronted by Elven blades. Cave-trolls are unintelligent creatures. They use their sense of smell more often than sight, generally being brought into combat by a chain around their neck, led along by a goblin tamer. In combat, Cave-trolls usually kill the figures that foolishly get too close to them, friend or foe, strategy notwithstanding. Cave-trolls, of all the types of trolls, are fairly tall in stature, being taller than the hill trolls of Mordor, but not as intelligent. Cave-trolls are omnivores, eating both meat and plants. Usually these trolls live with groups of goblins and fight alongside them or in groups of two or three in small caves. They are used by the armies of Sauron (though Sauron would typically forego these trolls in favor of Olog-hai, a stronger and smarter troll that could move in the sunlight without turning into stone). It is known that Cave-trolls turn into stone when exposed to direct sunlight. Cave Trolls have a very primitive form of language as depicted in The Hobbit.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_MEC_CAVE_TROLL_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Cave Troll is the primary mobile unit of the Goblin Kingdom. They replace the Knight. The are stronger than the knight, but require more production to build then the knight. The Cave Troll upgrades to the Landship instead of Cavalry. The Cave Troll does not require horses. The Cave Troll only has 3 moves.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_HELP_MEC_CAVE_TROLL">
			<Text>Replaces the Knight. Upgrades to Landship instead of Cavalry. Stronger but slower.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_CAVE_TROLL">
			<Text>Troll Skin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_CAVE_TROLL_HELP">
			<Text>+25% Defense</Text>
		</Row>
		-->
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MEC_TUNNEL">
			<Text>Tunnel</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_BUILDINGS_MEC_TUNNEL">
			<Text>The Goblins often built a network of branching caves and tunnels within their domain. The tunnels in Goblin-Town stretched out from the Misty Mountains south of the Mountains of Angmar to the High Pass in the Northern part of the mountain range. Most of the tunnels were carved by the Goblins, though they also incorporated pre-existing caverns and passages.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MEC_TUNNEL_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Tunnel network provides quick transportation (Airlift ability usually gained from building an airport) between goblin cities. You must build one in each city to travel between the cities with tunnels.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MEC_TUNNEL_HELP">
			<Text>Monument with Tunneling Quick Transport (airlift) Ability</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_MEC_SCAVENGING">
			<Text>While in Friendly Territory +20% [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength against units with Higher Tech. Destroying an enemy unit whose technology hasn't been discovered genearates 15% of the [ICON_RESEARCH] science required to research that tech.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_MEC_SCAVENGING_SHORT">
			<Text>Scavenging</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MEC_AZOG_NAME">
			<Text>Azog</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MEC_AZOG_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>The Defiler, King of Moria</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MEC_AZOG_LIVED">
			<Text>?-TA2799</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MEC_AZOG_DEFEATED_%">
			<Text>I yield. Cut off my head and be done with it. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MEC_AZOG_FIRSTGREETING_%">
			<Text>Do you smell it? The Scent of fear? You reek of it!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_GORKIL">
			<Text>Gorkil</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_SHELOB">
			<Text>Shelob</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_GREAT_GOBLIN">
			<Text>Great Goblin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_BOLG">
			<Text>Bolg</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_ORCOBAL">
			<Text>Orcobal</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_DROGOTH">
			<Text>Drogoth</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_LUG">
			<Text>Lug</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_BOLDOG">
			<Text>Boldog</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_BALCMEG">
			<Text>Balcmeg</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_SMAUG">
			<Text>Smaug</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>	
