<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 8/9/2021 10:55:01 PM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<!--Info on LEADER-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ZHONGLI">
			<Text>Zhongli</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ZHONGLI_CIV_IV">
			<Text>Zhongli</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_ZHONGLI_HEADING_1">
			<Text>[COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]!!!SPOILERS AHEAD!!![ENDCOLOR]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_ZHONGLI_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Archon War</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_ZHONGLI_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Early liyue</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_ZHONGLI_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Present</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_ZHONGLI_TEXT_1">
			<Text>[COLOR_WARNING_TEXT] Archon Quest 2 Spoilers! [ENDCOLOR] </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_ZHONGLI_TEXT_2">
			<Text>
				The Archon War was an era of various power struggles between gods that began several thousand years ago for unknown reasons, although scholars in Teyvat believe it began over seven divine seats in Celestia. While different regions settled their power struggles at different times, the era drew to a close 2,000 years ago after the final seat was claimed.
				With the end of an era came the establishment of a new order under the Seven Archons. They determined the seven elements in Teyvat and established the seven nations, determining their method of governance through their ideals and shaping their nations using their elemental powers. Zhongli being the oldest of all Archons and taking the seat as the Lord of Geo.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_ZHONGLI_TEXT_3">
			<Text>
				In the beginning, Liyue was a very rough and unfavorable terrain with little room for the growth of mortal man, however, with the guidance of the Lord of Geo himself, many a mortal were able to seek out the truth of their lives and find an honest living with the freedoms of all mortal leisure. Many Gods once attempted to rule over Liyue, but the one of true dominance and order reigned supreme. Many names were given to the Lord of Geo, those being Rex Lapis, Morax, or the man we now simply refer to as Zhongli. Ever one to endorse the growth of mortal civilization, Zhongli looked upon his nation of Liyue with warmth and kindness blessing them with great prosperity, law and wealth. Though this early era of Liyue was indeed prosperous, it was not without tiviality and struggle. Envious deities wished to see the Lord of Geo himself fall to ruin, many of those said foes would spread darkness and feindish monsters who sought to tear appart the very fabric of mortal civilization in Liyue
				[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				In those dark and trying times, Zhongli appointed great defenders of Liyue who all mortals would look up to and respect immensely. The name bestowed upon these honorable defenders were the Adepti and Yaksha. As the evil encroached the beginnings of Liyue, the humble defenders beat back the scouring darkness and freed the Liyue people of terrors and monsters, ushering in a newer era of peace and prosperity. Even in present Liyue do the citizens hold all adepti and yaksha in very high esteem for their courage and sacrifice in protecting Liyue.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_ZHONGLI_TEXT_4">
			<Text>
				In more recent times, The Lord of Geo has since staged his own death from his seat as a God. Durring a right of Rebirth, an annual celebration of respect and adoration for their lord, Liyue civilians make offerings to their omnipresent God, However, in the most recent celebration, The Lord of Geo descended from the sky in shambles. This was a mere act however, Zhongli had long known that the people of Liyue no longer had a need to follow in the footsteps of a God. The nation had grown to such a beautiful capacity and prosperity that the Lord of Geo himself saw fit to let the people guide themselves toward a bighter tomorrow. Though the people call his name in great love and adoration for all he had done, the mortal who he now walks his beautiful lands as hears their reverence for his name and smiles fondly and enjoys the pleasures of being a mortal in the land he himself created. Offering away his own Godhood in the form of a Gnosis, Zhongli now truly walks the lands of Liyue as a mortal and sees the highs and lows, the greatness and sorrow ~~ and the difficulties of money management
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_ZHONGLI_LIVED">
			<Text>??? - (living over 6000 years)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_ZHONGLI_NAME">
			<Text>Zhongli</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_ZHONGLI_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Lord of Geo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_ZHONGLI_TITLES_1">
			<Text>Archon of Liyue</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_ZHONGLI_TITLES_2">
			<Text>Rex Lapis</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Info on Civ-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_LIYUE_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Liyue</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_LIYUE_DESC">
			<Text>Liyue</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_LIYUE_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Liyue</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_LIYUE_HEADING_1">
			<Text>Profile</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_LIYUE_TEXT_1">
			<Text>
				Liyue is a very large and rugged terrain with high hills and mountains peppered across the countryside. Though there are many unforgiving and rough terrains across the nation, its not without a bounty of fertile untouched land and caves with rich and beautiful ores.
				[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				The people of Liyue have adatped to this terrain and are able to put the bountiful land to proper use and are very prosperous while maintaining a very high level of dignity.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_LIYUE_HEADING_2">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_LIYUE_TEXT_2">
			<Text>
				? years ago ― Guizhong, the Lord of Dust, befriends Morax. At some point, she and her people move north of Mt. Tianheng for reasons unknown. Morax and Guizhong establish the Guili Assembly,this civilization spanned the area between Mt. Tianheng and Stone Gate. It was extremely prosperous, flourishing under the trades of agriculture and mining, and became a trading hub.
				[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				? years ago ― Early civilizations in the Lisha region of Liyue are established at Dunyu Ruins, Lingju Pass, Qingxu Pool. At some point either before or during the Archon War, the civilizations at Lingju Pass and Qingxu Pool were destroyed and submerged underwater, only reemerging after the end of the Archon War.
				[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				3700 years ago ― Some time after the fall of the Guili Assembly, Morax takes his people south of Mt. Tianheng, where he establishes Liyue Harbor. He creates a contract with the adepti to defend it.
			</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LIYUE_1">
			<Text>Liyue Harbor</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LIYUE_2">
			<Text>Mt. Tianheng</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LIYUE_3">
			<Text>Dihua Marsh</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LIYUE_4">
			<Text>Wangshu Inn</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LIYUE_5">
			<Text>Qingce Village</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LIYUE_6">
			<Text>Jueyun Karst</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LIYUE_7">
			<Text>Qiaoying Village</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LIYUE_8">
			<Text>Bishui Plain</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LIYUE_9">
			<Text>Minlin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LIYUE_10">
			<Text>Qiongji Estuary</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LIYUE_11">
			<Text>Lisha</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LIYUE_12">
			<Text>Sea of Clouds</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LIYUE_13">
			<Text>The Chasm</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LIYUE_14">
			<Text>Guyun Stone Forest</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_LIYUE_0">
			<Text>Ganyu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_LIYUE_1">
			<Text>Xiao</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_LIYUE_2">
			<Text>Keqing</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_LIYUE_3">
			<Text>Beidou</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_LIYUE_4">
			<Text>Yanfei</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_LIYUE_5">
			<Text>Shenhe</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_LIYUE_6">
			<Text>Hu Tao</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_LIYUE_7">
			<Text>Qiqi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_LIYUE_8">
			<Text>Xiangling</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_LIYUE_9">
			<Text>Xingqiu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_LIYUE_10">
			<Text>Chongyun</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_LIYUE_DOM">
			<Text>
				Greetings to you, Zhongli, Lord of Geo! Long have you watched carefully over the lands of your home and countless others. The battles you fought in the years of the terrible archon war weigh heavily upon you and never leave your memory, though for the darkness that once nearly consumed your beloved nation was swept away by your mighty hand! For many years did Liyue develop and grow before your eyes and rightfully so! Your great desire to see fairness equality and order of law was a powerful foundation for the people of Liyue to grow into a strong united nation. The people of Liyue call your name once more to take the mantle of leader Can you build a civilization to stand the test of time?
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Zhongli Trait-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_GOD_OF_CONTRACTS">
			<Text>Each international [ICON_INTERNATIONAL_TRADE] trade route conntected to any city grants Liyue 5% [ICON_CULTURE] culture and will grant Liyue and the connected partner bonus[ICON_GOLD] and 1 [ICON_HAPPINESS_1]. Upon entering a new era, gain an additional [ICON_INTERNATIONAL_TRADE] trade route.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_GOD_OF_CONTRACTS_SHORT">
			<Text>God of Contracts</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Zhongli Uniques-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_ADEPTAL_WARRIOR">
			<Text>Adeptal Warrior</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_HELP_ADEPTAL_WARRIOR">
			<Text>The Adeptal Warrior is the cornerstone of Liyues defenses. Its unique fear aura terrifies nearby foes causing them to battle much weaker. SFlightly more  powerful than the Pikeman that it replaces.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_UNITS_ADEPTAL_WARRIOR_TEXT">
			<Text>
				Much like the old days of the archon war where Rex Lapis appointed Adepti to defend Liyue do these warriors derive from. Their vast combat experience makes them feared warriors across all 7 nations in Teyvat. Both respected by allies and feared by foes alike, the Adepti have long stood with Liyue to ensure peace is secured.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_ADEPTAL_WARRIOR_STRATEGY">
			<Text> The Adeptal Warrior is a replacement of the Pikeman. Wile sacrificing effective damage attacks against mounted foes, The adeptal Warrior weakens foes nearby with a terror aura. The immense power of the Adepti is well known by foes of any kind. Correct placement of the Adepti can change a great foe into an otherwise normal enemy with their defenses weakened!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FEIYUN_COMMERCE_GUILD">
			<Text>Feiyun Commerce Guild</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FEIYUN_COMMERCE_GUILD_HELP">
			<Text>The Feiyun Commerce Guild replaces the market, along with the same benefits,grants 5% production, additionally, each trade route from the city that has one built will yield 5% production</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_FEIYUN_COMMERCE_GUILD_TEXT">
			<Text>The Feiyun Commerce Guild is a main part of Liyue economic transit. The guild is a main exporter of goods and imports goods from other nations as well.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FEIYUN_COMMERCE_GUILD_STRATEGY">
			<Text>A very powerful suppliment to Liyues natural ability to generate additional culture from trade routes. Connecting trade routes to benefit yourself culturally and industrially is a main focal point to Liyue's success!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_STRENGTH_OF_THE_ADEPTI">
			<Text>Powerful Adeptal energy terrifies foes</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_STRENGTH_OF_THE_ADEPTI_HELP">
			<text>-10% enemy combat strength when near</text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>