<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
	  
<GameData>  
	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV_MEC_DWARVES_DESC">
			<Text>Kingdom of Durin's Folk</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV_MEC_DWARVES_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Dwarves</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV_MEC_DWARVES_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Dwarves</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV5_MEC_DWARVES_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Dwarves were a short, stocky race, a little taller than hobbits but much broader and heavier. Most Dwarves had thick, luxuriant beards in which they took great pride, and often forked or braided them and tucked them into their belts. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Thrór was a King of Durin's Folk, the father of Thrain II, and grandfather to Thorin Oakenshield. In early life, Thrór and his family lived in the dragon-plagued Grey Mountains. In TA 2589, when their halls came under attack by Cold-Drakes, his father Dáin I and younger brother Frór were both slain at their gates by a great Cold-Drake. Thrór inherited the kingship. Thrór led a small portion of the House of Durin to recolonize Erebor where they rediscovered the Arkenstone, the symbol of his right to rule. Under Thrór's leadership, Erebor prospered for over a century. Eventually the wealth of the kingdom attracted the attention of the dragon known as Smaug, who flew south and destroyed the kingdom, killing many Dwarves and driving away Thrór and his family, and other surviving dwarves. The majority of the survivors migrated to the Iron Hills, but some followed King Thrór, his son Thráin II, and grandson Thorin Oakenshield west into a long and homeless wandering. They eventually settled in the hills of Dunland where they made a living as best they could.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE] It is time for you to rule once again and lead the line of Durin to victory? Or will you let your greed and lust for gold bring about your downfall once more? Can you build a civilization that will stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV_MEC_DWARVES_PEDIA">
			<Text>After the First Age most tales telling of Dwarves are about the Dwarves of the line of Durin, who are commonly called Durin’s Folk or Longbeards. Durin I enjoyed a very long life and lived through most of the First Age. Every now and then through the following ages a Dwarf was born of this line that was so alike to Durin that he was considered to be Durin reborn. Prophecy told that Durin would be reborn seven times and the coming of Durin VII would mark the decline of the Dwarves. Durin II was born in the Second Age. It is not known exactly when, but he was in power when the smith Narvi built the west gate of Khazad-dûm in the year 750. His reign was an era of great prosperity in which the halls of Khazad-dûm were greatly expanded and the Noldorin Elves of Lindon moved into Eregion to trade with the Dwarves for mithril. Population boomed because many refugees from Belegost and Nogrod, which were destroyed at the end of the First Age, moved to Khazad-dûm. Durin III was in power around the year 1600 of the Second Age. He was gifted with the seventh and most powerful of the Dwarven Rings of Power. It was the Elven smith Celebrimbor and not Sauron who gave him the ring. The rings of power did not have the effects that Sauron had intended, possibly because Aulë had made the dwarves especially resistant to evil domination. The only apparent effect of the Dwarven rings was that the Dwarves became more greedy with gold lust, but they were not turned into wraiths like men. Sauron tried to recover the rings. Two he reclaimed fairly soon and four ended up in dragon hoards. Sauron did not reclaim the ring of Durin until the 2845th year of the Third Age when he captured Thráin II.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV5_MEC_DWARVES">
			<Text>Kingdom of Durin's Folk</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_EREBOR">
			<Text>Erebor</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_IRON_HILLS">
			<Text>Iron Hills</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_REDHORN_PASS">
			<Text>Redhorn Pass</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_SILVERLODE">
			<Text>Silverlode</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_LONELY_MOUNTAIN">
			<Text>Lonely Mountain</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_KHAZAD_DUM">
			<Text>Khazad Dum</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_BELEGOST">
			<Text>Belegost</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_NOGROD">
			<Text>Nogrod</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_GABILGATHOL">
			<Text>Gabilgathol</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_BLUE_MOUNTAINS">
			<Text>Blue Mountains</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_MICKLEBURG">
			<Text>Mickleburg</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_TUMUNZAHAR">
			<Text>Tumunzahar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_AZANULBIZAR">
			<Text>Azanulbizar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_AMON_RUDH">
			<Text>Amon Rudh</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_GLITTERING_CAVES">
			<Text>Glittering Caves</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_ANGHABAR">
			<Text>Anghabar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_MOUNT_DOLMED">
			<Text>Mount Dolmed</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_ERED_LUIN">
			<Text>Ered Luin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_SILVERTINE">
			<Text>Silvertine</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_CARADHRAS">
			<Text>Caradhras</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_FANUIDHOL">
			<Text>Fanuidhol</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_ERED_MITHRIN">
			<Text>Mithrin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_RAVENHILL">
			<Text>Ravenhill</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_HOLLOWHOLD">
			<Text>Hollowhold</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MEC_THROR">
			<Text>Thror</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MEC_THROR_PEDIA">
			<Text>Thror</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MEC_THROR">
			<Text>Thror Pedia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_MEC_GUARDIAN">
			<Text>Guardian</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_UNITS_ANTIQUITY_MEC_GUARDIAN">
			<Text>Each Dwarven citadel is a well-defended and massive complex of tunnels, workshops and great halls. For thousands of years these halls have been defended by stalwart and fearless warriors equipped with axe and shield. In all of Middle-earth there are few warriors who could stand toe-to-toe against a Dwarven Guardian. Every Dwarf is naturally strong and skilled with tools—the tools of war are no exception. Guardians have been called to march against countless throngs of Goblins in dark caves or ancient powerful dragons on high mountain summits. After so many lifetimes of protecting the priceless treasures of their brothers, the Guardians have become a soldier of Middle-earth to be both feared and respected.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_MEC_GUARDIAN_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Dwarven Guardians are the backbone of any Dwarven army. Equipped with heavy armor, massive shields, and a huge razor sharp axe, they are slow but powerful. They are an infantry unit that deals extra damage towards cities, thanks to the Siege Hammers promotion.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_HELP_MEC_GUARDIAN">
			<Text>Powerful, city destroying unit. Replaces the Swordsman.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MEC_DWARVEN_FORGE">
			<Text>Dwarven Forge</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_BUILDINGS_MEC_DWARVEN_FORGE">
			<Text>The Dwarves learned the knowlege of crafts from their creator Aule. In the Ages of Starlight, the Dwarves of the Blue Mountains fashioned the finest steel that the World had ever seen.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MEC_DWARVEN_FORGE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Dwarven Forge can only be constructed in a city with an improved source of Iron, Copper, Silver, or Gold. It increase the speed at which the city produces land units.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MEC_DWARVEN_FORGE_HELP">
			<Text>+15% [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production of Land Units.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Each source of Iron, Copper, Silver, or Gold worked by this City produces +1 [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production and +1 [ICON_CULTURE] Culture.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_MEC_KING_UNDER_THE_MOUNTAIN">
			<Text>Double quantaties for all mined luxury and strategic resources.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_MEC_KING_UNDER_THE_MOUNTAIN_SHORT">
			<Text>King Under the Mountain</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_THORIN">
			<Text>Thorin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_BALIN">
			<Text>Balin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_BIFUR">
			<Text>Bifur</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_BOFUR">
			<Text>Bofur</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_BOMBUR">
			<Text>Bombur</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_DORI">
			<Text>Dori</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_GIMLI">
			<Text>Gimli</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_FILI">
			<Text>Fili</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_KILI">
			<Text>Kili</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_GLOIN">
			<Text>Gloin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MEC_THROR_NAME">
			<Text>Thror</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MEC_THROR_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>King Under the Mountain</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MEC_THROR_LIVED">
			<Text>TA2790-TA2589</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MEC_THROR_DEFEATED_%">
			<Text>I am defeated and my treasures are yours, but one day I will reclaim what is rightfully mine.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MEC_THROR_FIRSTGREETING_%">
			<Text>I am Thror, King Under the Mountain! Behold the wealth and richess of my Kingdom.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_MEC_SIEGE_HAMMERS">
			<Text>Siege Hammers</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_MEC_SIEGE_HAMMERS_HELP">
			<Text>+25% vs Cities</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_MEC_DWARF">
			<Text>Dwarf</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_MEC_DWARF_HELP">
			<Text>-1 Movement</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>	
