<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
	  
<GameData>  
	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV_MEC_ARNOR_DESC">
			<Text>Arnor Kingdom</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV_MEC_ARNOR_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Arnor</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV_MEC_ARNOR_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Dunedain</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV5_MEC_ARNOR_TEXT_1">
			<Text>
				Arnor, i.e. the Northern Kingdom, was a kingdom of the Dúnedain in the land of Eriador in Middle-earth. It was founded at the end of the Second Age (SA 3320) by Elendil. Before the foundation of Arnor there was already a sizable Númenórean population living there, a result of the slow emigration of Númenóreans which had started under Tar-Meneldur and Tar-Aldarion. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE] Arnor's capital was Annúminas on Lake Evendim, but by TA 861 Fornost Erain had become the capital instead as Annúminas became depopulated. After the death of its tenth king, Eärendur, in 861, Arnor was shaken by civil war between the three sons of Eärendur. The eldest son, Amlaith, claimed Kingship over all Arnor but was reduced to only ruling the region of Arthedain as his kingdom, while the other sons founded the kingdoms of Cardolan and Rhudaur. Arnor was refounded in name by Arthedain's king Argeleb I, when Cardolan placed itself under the suzerainty of Arthedain. However, even Arthedain was eventually destroyed by the Witch King of Angmar. The people of Arnor were mostly wiped out by the wars, but the Hobbits survived in the Shire, men survived in Bree and probably other villages, and the Dúnedain of Arnor created new homes in the Angle south of Rivendell, where some of them became known as the Rangers of the North. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE] Elendil, Out of the Great Sea to Middle-earth you have come. In this place you will abide, and your heirs, unto the ending of the world. Can you build a civilization that will stand the test of time?
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV5_MEC_ARNOR">
			<Text>Arnor</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_CARDOLAN">
			<Text>Cardolan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_RHUDAUR">
			<Text>Rhudaur</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_FORNOST">
			<Text>Fornost</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_SOUTH_DOWNS">
			<Text>South Downs</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_ANNUMINAS">
			<Text>Annuminas</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_NENUIAL">
			<Text>Nenuial</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_ARTHEDAIN">
			<Text>Arthedain</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_LAKE_EVENDIM">
			<Text>Lake Evendim</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_WEATHER_HILLS">
			<Text>Weather Hills</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_EVENDIM_HILLS">
			<Text>Evendim Hills</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_TYRN_GORTHAD">
			<Text>Tyrn Gorthad</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_AMON_SOL">
			<Text>Amon Súl</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_OLD_FOREST">
			<Text>Old Forest</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_THARBAD">
			<Text>Tharbad</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_ELOSTIRION">
			<Text>Elostirion</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_NORBURY">
			<Text>Norbury</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_STADDLE">
			<Text>Staddle</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_EMYN_UIAL">
			<Text>Emyn Uail</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_ARCHET">
			<Text>Archet</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_COMBE">
			<Text>Combe</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_CHETWOOD">
			<Text>Chetwood</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_MIDGEWATER">
			<Text>Midgewater</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_LONE_LANDS">
			<Text>Lone Lands</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_ANDRATH">
			<Text>Andrath</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_SARN_FORD">
			<Text>Sarn Ford</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_WITHYWINDLE">
			<Text>Withywindle</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MEC_ELENDIL">
			<Text>Elendil</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MEC_ELENDIL_PEDIA">
			<Text>Elendil the Tall</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MEC_ELENDIL">
			<Text>
				Elendil (also known as Elendil the Tall (his height was recorded at a lofty 7' 10" / 2,41 m) or Elendil the Fair) (SA 3119 - SA 3441) was the father of Isildur and Anárion, and the first High King of Gondor and Arnor and first King of all the Dúnedain. He was known as a great warrior and a wise king, and a heroic figure among the Dúnedain, who loved every man, woman and child of Arnor and Gondor, and was loved by them in return. Elendil was born in 3119 of the Second Age in Númenor, son of Amandil, Lord of Andúnië and leader of the "Faithful" (those who remained loyal to the Valar), who maintained a strong friendship with the elves and preserved the old ways against the practices of Ar-Pharazôn and Sauron. He was married to an unnamed Númenórean woman no doubt of the same upbringing and noble blood to which they had two sons: Isildur and Anárion. It is not known whether she followed him to Middle-earth after the Fall of Númenor. Elendil, his sons Isildur and Anárion, and their supporters fled to Middle-earth at the Downfall of Númenor, sailing east in nine ships and founding the realms of Arnor and Gondor in Middle-earth in SA 3320. With them they took the Palantiri, the "Seeing Stones" that were given to the Lords of Andúnie by the elves of Tol Eressëa, and a seedling of Nimloth, the White Tree of Númenor. Elendil lived in Arnor, where he founded the city of Annúminas. His son Anárion founded the city of Minas Anor in Anórien, and his son Isildur founded Minas Ithil in Ithilien. Across the Anduin the city of Osgiliath was built. Across the realms towers are built for the Palantíri, with which the realms keep contact. In time Sauron returned to Middle-earth, establishing a stronghold in Mordor, next to Gondor. In SA 3428, he attacked seizing Minas Ithil. Isildur fled north to his father, leaving Anárion in charge of Gondor. In SA 3434, Elendil and Isildur returned south together with the Elven High King Gil-galad and their combined armies, in the Last Alliance of Elves and Men. After defeating Sauron's armies and advancing into Mordor itself, the armies of Men and Elves settled into a siege of the main tower of Sauron: Barad-dûr. During this siege Anárion was killed.At the end of the long siege in the year SA 3441, Sauron came out to personally do battle with his enemies. Elendil, together with the Elven-king Gil-galad, overthrew Sauron, but they were both killed in the process, and Elendil's sword broke when he fell. Elendil's son Isildur used his father's broken sword to cut the One Ring from Sauron's hand. Vanquished, Sauron's spirit fled. Isildur built a hidden tomb for his father on the summit of the beacon hill of Halifirien.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_MEC_WATCHER">
			<Text>Watcher</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_UNITS_MEC_WATCHER">
			<Text>The Rangers of the North were also known as Watchers. See the Rangers Civilopedia entry for more information.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_MEC_WATCHER_STRATEGY">
			<Text>
				Use the Watcher for scouting out goody huts and barbarian encampments. 
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_HELP_MEC_WATCHER">
			<Text>Replaces the Scout. Ranged unit as strong as an archer and can pick bonuses from goody huts</Text>
		</Row>
		-->
		
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_MEC_RANGER">
			<Text>Ranger</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_UNITS_MEC_RANGER">
			<Text>The Rangers were described by the Bree-folk as taller and darker, with strange skills in sight and hearing.[1] They usually wore grey or dark green cloaks with no identifying ornaments except a six-pointed cloak-clasp in the shape of a star. Another identifying feature was that all of them wore a green longcoat. Equipped primarily with swords and bows, they were quick, versatile, and experienced riders. Characteristically elusive and enigmatic, the Rangers spent most of their lives in the wild, visiting towns and villages only on rare occasions. The Rangers were led by Chieftains. These Chieftains could trace their lines back to Isildur himself and his father Elendil. Though the Chieftains were designated figures of authority for the Rangers, the scattered people had no official headquarters or capital after the disintegration of Arnor and possibly lived in temporary camps scattered about the wilderness. For over a thousand years, the Rangers of the North faithfully preserved the Line of Elendil and the ways of the Dúnedain and the ancient heirlooms of the Heir of Isildur such as the Shards of Narsil, Star of Elendil, Sceptre of Annúminas, and the Ring of Barahir. Like all Dúnedain, they were very friendly with the Elves, particularly those of Rivendell, where each heir would be born and raised. They secretly guarded and protected Eriador, which included the Shire unbeknownst to its people from spies and invaders. At the time of the War of the Ring, the Rangers of the North were led by Aragorn, future king of the reunited kingdoms of Gondor and Arnor. But despite Aragorn's leadership, most of the Rangers remained scattered and diminished. Therefore, when the ranger Halbarad endeavored to aid Aragorn in the War, he could muster no more than thirty Rangers to join him.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_MEC_RANGER_STRATEGY">
			<Text>A stronger composite bowman that is a recon unit and makes for an excellent scout. Can detect invisible units.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_HELP_MEC_RANGER">
			<Text>Replaces the Composite Bowman but is a Recon Unit. Extra combat and ranged strength and ignores terrain cost. Can detect invisible units.</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MEC_BARROW">
			<Text>Barrow</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_BUILDINGS_BARROW">
			<Text> A Barrow is a mound of dirt over a grave. Barrows in Middle-earth include those on the Barrow-downs and the ones before the gates of Edoras, where the kings of Rohan are buried. Frodo Baggins, Meriadoc Brandybuck, Peregrin Took, and Sam Gamgee all ended up in a barrow after their capture by a Barrow-wight in the Barrow-downs. The barrow was illuminated by a pale greenish light and many treasures were piled in the passage where the four hobbits were held. Merry, Pippin, and Sam sleep, as if under an enchantment, throughout their time in the barrow and so don't see Frodo use a sword to cut off the Barrow-wight's hand when it comes after them. Once Frodo summons Tom Bombadil, Tom opens low door in the barrow and destroys the Barrow-wight. He and Frodo carry the other hobbits out of the barrow and Tom Bombadil brings a load of treasure out of the barrow to break the spell of the barrow and keep other wights away from it. The four hobbits get their Barrow-blades from the barrow, which is said to be the grave of the last prince of Cardolan. The barrows in front of Edoras are arranged according to the lines of the kings of Rohan. The nine graves on the right are of the first line of the kings, starting with Eorl and the seven on the left are from the second, beginning with Fréaláf Hildeson and ending with Théoden. The barrows are covered with a white flower, simbelmynë, which blooms all year round.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MEC_BARROW_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The barrow is a more powerful shrine that provides +2 Faith and +1 Culture instead.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MEC_BARROW_HELP">
			<Text>Shrine but with +2 Faith and +1 Culture</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_MEC_KING_OF_ALL_THE_DUNEDAIN">
			<Text>Culture cost of acquiring tiles reduced by 33%. Pay 50% less for Recon unit maintenance. Recon units can choose the rewards from Goody Huts and have +1 Sight.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_MEC_KING_OF_ALL_THE_DUNEDAIN_SHORT">
			<Text>King of all the Dunedain</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MEC_ELENDIL_NAME">
			<Text>Elendil</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MEC_ELENDIL_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>The Tall</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MEC_ELENDIL_LIVED">
			<Text>SA3119-SA3441</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MEC_ELENDIL_DEFEATED_%">
			<Text>Today I am defeated, but my heirs will destroy you and your evils before the end of this world.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MEC_ELENDIL_FIRSTGREETING_%">
			<Text>Out of the Great Sea to Middle-earth I am come. In this place I will abide, and my heirs, unto the ending of the world.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_ARANARTH">
			<Text>Aranarth</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_HALBARAD">
			<Text>Halbarad</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_VALANDIL">
			<Text>Valandil</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_ELDACAR">
			<Text>Eldacar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_ARANTAR">
			<Text>Arantar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_TARCIL">
			<Text>Tarcil</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_TARONDOR">
			<Text>Tarondor</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_ELENDUR">
			<Text>Elendur</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_AMLAITH">
			<Text>Amlaith</Text>
		</Row>

	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>	
