<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
	  
<GameData>  
	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV_MEC_EASTERLINGS_DESC">
			<Text>Easterling Kingdoms</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV_MEC_EASTERLINGS_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Easterlings</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV_MEC_EASTERLINGS_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Easterling</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV5_MEC_EASTERLINGS_TEXT_1">
			<Text>
				Easterlings, commonly known as the Men of Darkness, were a race of Men who lived in the vast and uncharted lands of Rhûn, east of Mordor and the Sea of Rhun. Easterlings were enemies of the Free Peoples and were allies of Sauron. There were many different nations and kingdoms of Easterlings living in the vast lands of Rhûn. These ranged from civilized empires to barbaric horse nomads of the open steppes. [NEWLINE]
				During the Third Age, the Easterlings frequently attacked Gondor and the lands bordering Rhun. In TA 490 they invaded Gondor, passing through Dagorlad and starting a series of wars that lasted sixty years until they were finally defeated in TA 550 by Turambar, the ninth King of Gondor. Afterwards, Gondor subdued some of them and took from them a large area of land between the Kingdom of Rhovanion and Mordor including the Sea of Rhûn.[NEWLINE]
				Gondor held on to these territories for a few hundred years but began to lose them over time. In TA 1248 the Easterlings once again clashed with Gondor in a series of skirmishes but were still not powerful or organized enough to stand against Gondor’s power. Though defeated the Easterlings would not have to wait long, for Gondor soon fell into decline and civil war. Afterwards, the Easterlings remained peaceful until the mid-nineteenth century when they were again powerful enough to attack the west. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE] 
				Khamul, the Black Easterling, the time has come for you to reunite the Easterling Kingdoms and assault the Free Peoples of Middle Earth. Will you enslave your enemies or succumb to them? Can you build a civilization that will stand the test of time?
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIV5_MEC_EASTERLINGS">
			<Text>Easterlings</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_RHUN">
			<Text>Rhun</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_HILDORIEN">
			<Text>Hildorien</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_RHUN_SEA">
			<Text>Rhun Sea</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_BALCHOTH">
			<Text>Balchoth</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_KALORME">
			<Text>Kalorme</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_ROMENOR">
			<Text>Romenor</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_BROWNLANDS">
			<Text>Brownlands</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_OROCARNI">
			<Text>Orocarni</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_HELCAR">
			<Text>Helcar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_RED_MOUNTAINS">
			<Text>Red Mountains</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_BAB_LON">
			<Text>Bab-lon</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_NINWI">
			<Text>Ninwi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_TRUI">
			<Text>Trui</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_RUM">
			<Text>Rum</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_CUIVIENEN">
			<Text>Cuiviened</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_ITHRYN_LUIN">
			<Text>Ithryn Luin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_MORINEHTAR">
			<Text>Morinehtar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_ROMESTAMO">
			<Text>Romestamo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_RHUN_HILLS">
			<Text>Rhun Hills</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MEC_EASTLANDS">
			<Text>Eastlands</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MEC_KHAMUL_PEDIA">
			<Text>Khamul</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MEC_KHAMUL">
			<Text>Khamul</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MEC_KHAMUL">
			<Text>Khamul</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_MEC_WAINRIDER">
			<Text>Wainrider</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_UNITS_ANTIQUITY_MEC_WAINRIDER">
			<Text>
				The Wainriders were a confederation of Easterling and Southron tribes who were united by their hate of Gondor, fueled by the dark lord Sauron. Following the Great Plague which weakened Gondor, they started their attacks in TA 1856, defeating the Gondorian army and killing King Narmacil II. They rode in great chariots (which gave them their name), and raided the lands of Rhovanion, destroying or enslaving its people. Gondor gradually lost all of its possessions east of Anduin to them. The thirtieth King of Gondor, Calimehtar son of Narmacil, defeated the Wainriders at the Field of Celebrant, buying some rest for his land. However the Wainriders struck back in TA 1944, allying themselves with the Haradrim of Near Harad and the Variags of Khand. Before this they had been expanding their power southward, beyond Mordor, and had come into conflict with the tribes of Khand and the eastern Haradrim. But eventually these men allied under their universal hate of the West. They managed to kill King Ondoher and all his heirs, but instead of riding on to Minas Anor and taking the city, they paused to celebrate. Meanwhile, general Eärnil of Gondor's southern army rode north to defend his king, but he came too late to rescue Ondoher, but he did manage to annihilate the Wainriders. Eärnil was crowned king. After this defeat the might of the Wainriders was broken, and they retreated east. They still held Rhovanion, but never troubled Gondor again until the War of the Ring.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_MEC_WAINRIDER_STRATEGY">
			<Text>
				Wainrdiers are fast ranged units, deadly on open terrain, and the first unit to require a Strategic resource - Horses. They are more powerful than the Archer and can move twice the distance on open terrain (4 MPs), allowing them to reach elements of the enemy army other units can't. However, Wainrdiers suffer a horrible movement penalty when entering Forest, Jungle or Hill tiles (unless roads have been constructed in them). Moreover, they're too bulky to use natural terrain defense, and unlike other mounted units, cannot move after attacking!
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_HELP_MEC_WAINRIDER">
			<Text>First mounted unit of the game, but unlike the Chairiot Archer is a melee mounted unit. Can move after attacking. Requires Horses. Replaces the Chairiot Archer.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_UNITS_MEDIEVAL_MEC_HALBERD">
			<Text>
				The Easterlings had three principal weapons: their pike, the scimitar, and the composite bow. The steel-bladed wooden halberd came in two sizes: the nine-foot halberd was used for porcupine formations and phalanx marches, while the five-foot one was used as a basic soldier's weapon. All halberds were spiked on the top (on the five-foot one it had a pike on the bottom too) and had downward-curving, serrated axe-blades, and below that halberds were backed by a curved spike; on the nine-foot one it was used to trip enemy horses while on the five-foot one it was used for piercing armor and deflecting if not disarming enemy blades. The axe blade featured a hole creating the curve. This was a truly versatile weapon that could be used both offensively and defensively.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_MEC_HALBERD">
			<Text>Halberdman</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_MEC_HALBERD_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Halberdman is a next-generation Spearman, armed with a much longer and deadlier weapon and breastplates. It receives a bonus when fighting against mounted units, which makes it pretty much the only unit that can hope to stand up against a rampaging Knight. A Halberdman fortified in defensive terrain is a Knight's worst nightmare. Halberdman are, however, weak versus other melee units and tend to be severely damaged by siege weapons used to defend cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_UNIT_HELP_MEC_HALBERD">
			<Text>Medieval Era front-line unit effective at taking out Mounted Units. Generates points towards Golden Ages with kills. Replaces the Pikeman</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_MEC_SHADOW_OF_THE_EAST">
			<Text>Landlocked cities recieve a free Caravansary. +2[ICON_GOLD] Gold per land trade route. 1 Free Trade Route slot available at the start of the game.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_MEC_SHADOW_OF_THE_EAST_SHORT">
			<Text>Shadow of the East</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_ULFANG">
			<Text>Ulfang</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_ULFAST">
			<Text>Ulfast</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_ULWORTH">
			<Text>Ulworth</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_ULDOR">
			<Text>Uldor</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_BOR">
			<Text>Bor</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_BORLAD">
			<Text>Borlad</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_BORLACH">
			<Text>Borlach</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_BORTHAND">
			<Text>Borthand</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_BRODDA">
			<Text>Brodda</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag ="TXT_KEY_SPY_MEC_MALTOK">
			<Text>Maltok</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MEC_KHAMUL_NAME">
			<Text>Khamul</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MEC_KHAMUL_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>The Black Easterling</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MEC_KHAMUL_LIVED">
			<Text>SA-3/25/3019</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MEC_KHAMUL_DEFEATED_%">
			<Text> I have failed. Today the golden army has fallen.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MEC_KHAMUL_FIRSTGREETING_%">
			<Text>I come from yonder. I am Khamul, the Black Easterling, Shadow of the East, and Dragon King. Have you seen my golden army?</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>	
